Joseph Senecal - Backend Software Engineer

jasenecal2@gmail.com || 802.399.8647 || Broomfield, CO || GitHub || LinkedIn

Personal Statement

As a former educator, wilderness guide and retail manager, I brought a wide range of diverse experiences with me when I became a software developer in 2022. I am an accomplished mentor with a compassionate and demanding leadership style, an inclusive and blameless team culture, and a firm belief that by building authentic and vulnerable relationships we can build work cultures that promote a successful business by enabling individuals to achieve their highest potentials.

Employment History

Lead Engineer | Nobody Wants to Buy a Ticket, remote | August 2024 - present

- Work directly with company leadership to design and implement a ticket pricing API.
- Learning Rust, Python and related web frameworks to help direct early tech stack decisions.

Backend Engineer | FORM, remote | September 2022 - January 2024

- Regularly delivered small to medium-sized projects within a well-established Ruby on Rails monolith and several other microservices.
- Routinely diagnosed and resolved bugs and worked to maintain aging infrastructure.
- Participated in the entire SDLC with a remote, globally distributed Professional Services team utilizing an Agile workflow to help deliver 3.9Million in Services revenue in 2023.

Bakery Supervisor | Whole foods Market, Boulder CO | November 2017 - Dec 2021

- Managed a diverse team of bakers, decorators, baristas and merchandisers to ensure custom orders were met, product was always stocked, and that customers' needs were met.
- Provided all onboarding and training, ensured regulatory and safety compliance, and balanced a caring and compassionate environment with high standards to achieve best-in-company sales.

Teacher | Denver Public Schools & DSST Charter Network, Denver CO | Nov 2013 -Sep 2017

- Created meaningful and authentic relationships with students and their families.
- Balanced a caring and demanding style of mentoring to forster students' confidence and create a safe space for the often vulnerable work of learning.
- Achieved best-in-the-nation improvement in grade-level Algebra performance.

Skills

Ruby • Python • JavaScript • Rust • HTML • Rails • Sidekiq • Kafka • PostgreSQL • CI/CD • Docker • Git • AGILE Workflow • Leadership • Mentoring • Communication • Teamwork • Independent Motivation • Lifelong Learning • Mission Driven

My Portfolio | Deployed | Code

This front-end-only project provides a little more information about myself, as well as a curated portfolio of select projects from my GitHub profile.

Education and Training

Turing School of Software Design Jan - Aug 2022, Certificate of Completion Backend Engineering, ACCET accredited, 1500 hours over 7 months.

Vassar College Aug 2008 - May 2012, BA Biology